这是你要的东西
This is what you wanted.
求你  放我走吧
Now, please, let me go.
哎呦
Whoops.
等你清理干净了
You know, once you clean that up,
或许我们可以再...
maybe we could go for a, um, round...
来个第三轮
three?
你不用再跟我说一遍了  或许该说是"第三遍"
You do not have to tell me twice, or should I say thrice?
早啊  亲爱的们
Good morning, my darlings!
母亲  我真心希望你过来之前能先来电话
Mother, I really wish you would call before you came over.
我不想打断你俩小情人
Well, I don't want to risk interrupting you two love birds
那个什么  但看来我还是打断了
in the middle of you know what, and it looks like I have
你俩那个什么
interrupted you in the middle of you know...
还用上瓜了啊
what and with a melon.
天呐  我不想多说什么  但是该用室温的
My, my. Not judging, but room temperature.
母亲
Mother. I --
您什么事
What -- What is it you want?
我希望我儿子能满足我一个小小请求
I want for my son to grant me a very simple wish.
我的出版商认为
Now, it seems that my publisher says
我的自助书如果想登上畅销榜
that for my self-help book to make the best-seller list,
我需要一位名人的背书
I need a celebrity endorsement
而且不是一般的名人
and not just any celebrity endorsement --
得是非同小可的背书
the endorsement of endorsements.
母亲  我乐意为你的书写点好评
Mother, I would be happy to write something for your book.
奥普拉
Oprah.
我需要奥普拉
I need Oprah.
你认识奥普拉吗
Uh, do you even know Oprah?
不啊
No, I do not.
你肯定认识认识奥普拉的人
Well, you must know someone who knows Oprah, but --
如果我保证去试试  你能离开吗
If I promise to try, will you leave?
我立刻离开
Poof. I am gone.
对了  说来好笑  亲爱的
Oh, you know, it's so funny, darling,
我也有这套便服
'cause I have that same negligee,
但上面有老虎爪印  这样的
but, of course, it's in a little tiger print, so it's...
继续做爱吧  亲爱的
Well, resume your lovemaking, darling.
莱恩和埃斯波遇到件凶杀案
Hey, Ryan and Espo have caught a homicide.
要一起去吗
You want to join them?
何必  这里就有犯罪现场
Why? Got a crime scene right here.
我母亲刚刚把性致干掉了
My mother just killed the mood.
好的  宝贝  我回头打给你
Uh-huh. Yeah, okay, baby. I'll call you later.
这里信号太差了
Reception's terrible in here.
起得早还是睡得晚
Early morning or late night?
都有
Oh! Both.
珍妮睡不着  因此怀孕
Jenny can't sleep, which, in her crazy,
九个月的逻辑混乱的她认为  出于团结
nine-month-pregnant logic, means -- out of solidarity --
我也不能睡
I'm not allowed to sleep, either.
还不算太糟
Oh, well, could be worse.
你不像被害人  被人置于
You could be granted the eternal sleep
永远的安睡中了  他叫什么
like our victim, whose name is?
拉斯·克洛斯
Lars Cross.
一家石油勘探公司的声纳技师
He's a sonar technician for an oil exploration company.
嗯  切萨皮克能源公司
Yeah, Chesapeake Energy.
据说他原本在土耳其为他们工作
Apparently, he was doing an overseas job for them in Turkey,
但他因为严重矿工而被解雇
but he got fired for missing too much work.
从他的护照来看
According to his passport,
他三天前才回到美国
he only got back to the States three days ago.
如果他刚被解雇  又怎么能买得起
If he was just fired, how could he afford
这么多酷炫的新玩具
all those wonderful, new toys?
那些不算什么
That's nothing.
他楼下还停了一辆崭新的保时捷911
Got a brand-new Porsche 911 downstairs
据说是现金支付的
that he apparently paid cash for,
而且他刚在沿街一家银行
and he just leased a safe-deposit box
租下了一个保险箱
at a bank down the street.
警探们  我推测  被害人
Well, detectives, I deduce that our victim's
突然的暴富是跟
sudden influx of cash had something to do
他...没有头
with the fact that -- He has no head!
哥们  说真的  不能提个醒吗
Dudes, seriously, give a guy a heads up.
让开  卡塞尔
Make way, Castle! Oh!
死亡时间  晚上10点到午夜之间
Time of death -- between 10:00 p.m. and midnight.
拉斯被用胶带缠在了那把椅子上
Lars was strapped to that chair with duct tape.
死后瘀伤表明他先遭了折磨
Perimortem bruising indicates that he was tortured
才被凶手砍头  用的是
before the killer decapitated him with...
刀
Sword!
土耳其弯刀
A Turkish scimitar?!
我查了  没有指纹
Ah! I checked -- no fingerprints.
是被害人自己的
It's from the victim's collection.
看来  拉斯真的很喜欢中东文化
Apparently, Lars is really into the Middle East.
那一带本就以可怕的砍头文明
Oh, a region known for its sordid history of beheading.
但是
And yet...
拉斯却是在曼哈顿被人砍头的
Lars was beheaded here in Manhattan.
或许拉斯错不该
Perhaps Lars made the mistake
把故事结局告诉了国王
of telling the king the ending of the story.
是吧
Am I right?
《一千零一夜》
"1001 Arabian Nights."
真是的  我好震惊
Truly, I am shocked.
你们怎么会都不知道
How is it that none of you know the story
《一千零一夜》
of "1001 Arabian Nights"?
我们高中时不是死书呆
We weren't nerds in high school.
好吧  你们走运  我现在开讲
Fair enough. Lucky for you, class is now in session.
在《一千零一夜》的故事中
In the story "1001 Arabian Nights,"
一位嫉妒心很强的国王每晚都要换个少女睡
a jealous king would sleep with a new young maiden every night,
然后就砍了她的头  这样别人就不能占有她了
then have her beheaded so no other men could have her.
那么这是个关于厌女连环杀手的故事
So, it's a story about a misogynistic serial killer?
不  是的  但不是
No. Well, yes, but no.
在故事中  为了制止杀戮
In the story, to stop the bloodshed,
一位名叫谢赫拉莎德的年轻少女
a young maiden by the name of Scheherazade
为国王编了一个引人入胜的故事
wove a fascinating tale for the king,
但她却不肯把结局告诉他
but she refused to tell him the ending,
逼他留她的命到第二晚
forcing him to keep her alive till the next night
让她讲完故事
so she could finish the story.
她每晚都讲个新故事  讲了一千零一夜
She told him a new story every night for 1001 nights
最终  国王娶了她
till finally, the king married her,
这说明了一个人会讲故事有多重要
which really says a lot about the power of a good storyteller.
但却完全不能说明被害人为什么被杀
Yet tells us nothing about why our victim was killed.
是吗
Or does it?
被害人遭到折磨
Our victim was tortured
是因为凶手  就像国王  想要什么
because like the killer, like the king, wanted something.
被害人的姐姐会去分局见我
Well, our victim's sister is meeting me in the precinct.
或许她能告诉我凶手想要什么
Maybe she can shed some light on what that thing was.
我去申请搜查令检查拉斯的新保险箱
I'll pull a warrant for Lars' new safe-deposit box,
看是否有凶手要的东西的线索
see if there's a clue as to what our killer was after.
是奥普拉的助理
This is Oprah's assistant.
我得去接
Um, I'll take this.
你们...
Uh, you guys...
先去吧
head out without me.
我...
I'll...
稍后就去分局
be heading to the precinct in just a little while.
拜托  多好的梗啊
Guys, these are comedy gold.
真是的  喂
Seriously. Hello?
-不好笑  -声音断断续续的  我听不清
- Not funny. - You're breaking up. I can't hear you.
-是啊  -稍等
- I know. - Just one second.
这里有信号吗
Are you getting reception?
谢谢  喂
Thank you. Hello?
是的
Yes.
其实  不是我的书
Well, actually, it's not about one of my books.
而是我母亲的书
It's about my mother's.
我要是在开玩笑就好了
No, I-I only wish I was joking.
-你是警察吗  -天呐
- Are you a cop? - Geez!
我不认得你
I don't recognize you,
我在楼里住了好多年了
and I've lived in this building for years.
我是跟警察一伙儿的
I'm actually with the cops.
我可以把手稿给你发去吗
I can send you the manuscript?
我知道凶手是谁
I know who the killer is.
你能...稍等一下
Can you -- Uh, Can you h-hold -- hold one moment?
是拉斯的前男友  马克
It was Lars' ex-boyfriend, Mark.
昨晚9点左右  马克在使劲敲拉斯的门
Last night around 9:00, Mark was banging on Lars' door,
说拉斯欠他钱  还威胁他还钱
said Lars owed him money and that he better pay up or else.
稍等
H-H-Hang on.
我可以再给你回...
Uh, c-can I call you right --
喂
Hello?
该死
Shoot.
我们刚刚说到
All right, where were...
哪了
we?
她人呢
Where'd she go?
克洛斯女士  你弟弟回国后
Ms. Cross, your brother appears to have come into
似乎一下拿到了很多钱
a great deal of money upon his return to the country,
但我们查过他的财务记录
but we checked his financials,
毫无记录表明钱的来源
and there's no record where it came from.
你知道吗
Do you have any idea?
不知道
None.
我知道他去土耳其时身无分文
I know for a fact he was broke when he left for Turkey.
他在国内或国外有什么敌人吗
Did he have any enemies at home or abroad?
没有
No.
他跟大家都处得很好
He got along with everyone.
包括他前男友  马克吗
Ever his ex-boyfriend, Mark?
据卡塞尔说  一位邻居听到
According to Castle, a neighbor overheard
拉斯的前任昨晚在他公寓外大吼
Lars' ex yelling outside of his apartment last night.
你弟弟欠他钱吗
Did your brother owe him money?
是马克替拉斯支付了一些哥大的学费
Mark helped pay for Lars' tuition at Columbia.
拉斯没还钱  是吧
Lars never paid him back, did he?
是啊  他们分手了
No. They broke up.
事实上  他接受去土耳其的工作主要
In fact, getting away from Mark was the main reason
就是为了离开马克
he took that job in Turkey.
马克  你跟拉斯以前是一对儿
So, Mark, you used to date Lars.
据这些报告显示
Well, according to these reports,
他这一年间
he called the cops on you
十多次报警告你
over a dozen times in the past year.
我有时会太过冲动
I sometimes get overly dramatic.
没办法
What can I do?
我是双鱼嘛  但我放下拉斯了  向前看了
I am a Pisces, but I am over Lars, and I moved on.
据一名目击者说
Not according to a witness
你昨晚还威胁他来着
who saw you threatening him last night.
是啊
Oh. Yes.
我经常威胁他
I threatened him -- a lot.
我给了他两万交学费
All right, I gave him 20 grand to get his degree,
我得到了什么样的感谢呢
and what thanks do I get?
他甩了我  还出国了
He dumps me and leaves the country.
现在时隔两个月  他就回来了
And now he's back two months later,
还开着保时捷到处跑
rolling around in a Porsche, so, yeah.
所以我是有点气疯
I went a little mental.
是啊  如果"有点气疯"
Sure, if by going "a little mental,"
是指折磨并杀害你前任
you mean torturing and killing your ex.
什么
What?
拉斯死了吗
Lars is -- is dead?!
天呐
Oh, my --
你们以为是我干的
Y-You think I did it?
天呐
Oh, G...
拉斯是我的挚爱
Lars was the love of my life.
我绝对不会
I-I could never just...
听着  我离开时拉斯还活着
Look, Lars was alive when I left him.
我发誓
I swear to you.
-那是几点  -9:30吧
- What time was that? - 9:30?
我叫优步去了上城区
I Ubered up town.
在一家酒吧碰到了几个朋友
I-I met some friends at a bar
然后就借酒浇愁到凌晨2点
and drank away my sorrows till 2:00 a.m.
好吧  就算
All right, let's just, uh, suppose
你说的是真的
that you are telling the truth.
在拉斯家发生了什么
What happened at Lars'?
他让我进去了  为所有事都道了歉
He let me in, apologized for everything,
还说给他一天时间去取钱还我
and said he just needed a day to get the cash to pay me b--
天呐  他说的是实话吗
Wait. He was telling the truth?
什么实话
The truth about what?
他一副疑神疑鬼的样子
He was acting all paranoid.
他从土耳其偷运了什么东西回来
He had smuggled something back from Turkey,
他的搭档觉得他出卖了他
and his partner thought he had double-crossed him.
等等  什么搭档
Whoa, whoa. Hold on. What partner?
我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
真的  我以为那都是他编的
Honestly, I just thought he was making it all up
是为了不还我钱
so th-that he wouldn't have to pay me.
你肯定很生气吧
I bet that pissed you off, huh?
没有
Well, no.
是的  但我也没杀他啊
I -- Well, yeah, I-it did, but I didn't kill him!
我只是拿走了他的笔记本当抵押
All right, I just took his laptop as collateral.
他是因此被杀的吗
Is that why he was killed?
我们需要你交出笔记本
We're gonna need that laptop.
马克的不在场证明证实了  他说的是实话
Mark's alibi checks out here. He was telling the truth.
你觉得拉斯偷运了什么回来
So, what do you think Lars was smuggling?
他当时在土耳其
Well, he was in Turkey,
那里可是阿富汗的海洛因运输渠道
which is the heroin pipeline from Afghanistan.
不  不是毒品
Hmm. No. Wasn't drugs.
为什么
Why not?
因为拉斯是被人用土耳其弯刀砍了头
Because Lars was beheaded by a scimitar.
我体内的讲故事人
Well, the storyteller inside me
希望缘由能更
craves an explanation for more --
-扯淡  -对
- Farfetched? - Yeah.
海盗宝藏  冷聚变
Pirate's booty? Cold fusion?
-外星人尸体  -不
- Alien cadavers? - No.
那些理论都太荒唐了
Those are all ridiculous theories.
你说"外星人尸体"了吗
Did you say "alien cadavers," though?
我看过一部纪录片
Because I saw a documentary once --
卡塞尔  你问话的那个
Hey, Castle, um, what was the name
女人叫什么来着  拉斯的邻居
of that woman that you interviewed -- Lars' neighbor?
我没问到名字
I didn't get her name.
我的警员好像忘记把她的供词放进案卷里了
I think my UNIs forgot to put her statement in this file.
我大部分时间
I swear, most of my time
都花在检查别人的文件工作上了
is spent checking people's paperwork.
你是不是出手后悔了
You're suffering from a little buyer's remorse.
是啊  这就是人生残忍的笑话
Yeah, it's one of life's cruel jokes.
你得偿所愿
You get exactly what you wished for,
却发现这根本不是你想要的
only to find that it wasn't what you wanted at all.
不  我喜欢做警监
No, I love being a captain.
只是我有时候觉得
It's just, sometimes it feels like
自己更像幼儿园老师
I'm more of a kindergarten teacher.
-我是警长  -让开
- I'm a sergeant. - Get out of my way.
我刚有了重大突破
I just broke this case wide open.
其实  是我有突破  我先说吧
Actually, I did, so I'll go first.
不  还是我先说吧
No, I think I'll go first.
我的突破比你的大
Mine's bigger than yours.
想得美
You wish, pal.
两位
Guys...
乖乖的  小点声
play nice -- indoor voices.
埃斯波先说
Espo goes first.
瞧  她就知道
See, she knows.
我打开了拉斯的保险箱
So, I opened Lars' safe-deposit box
里面有40万美元现金
and found 400 G's in cash.
肯定是毒品钱  看你怎么破
Gots to be drug money. Beat that.
轻松  我从马克那里拿到了拉斯加密的电脑
Easy -- got Lars' encrypted laptop from Mark,
查明了他在偷运什么
found out what he was smuggling,
不是毒品
and it wasn't drugs.
什么
What?
不  拉斯不是毒贩
No. Lars wasn't a drug dealer.
他是个盗墓者
He was a tomb raider.
莱恩  你能放大这里吗
R-Ryan, can you zoom in on that, please?
我见过这个标志
I've seen that symbol.
对  在拉斯公寓里
Yes, uh at Lars' apartment.
记得那些关于《一千零一夜》的书吗
You remember there was all those books on "1001 Arabian Nights."
我觉得那个标志
I think that symbol...
就在其中一本书上
...was on one of the books.
没错  就是这个
Yes. Here it is.
所罗门封印
The Seal of Solomon.
"所罗门据称蕴含
"The Seal of Solomon was believed to be imbued
神秘力量
with mystical powers,
包括将灯神封入灯中的能力
including the ability to seal genies into lamps.
在《阿拉丁和神灯》的故事中
In the tale of 'Aladdin and the Magic Lamp,'
阿拉丁在一个山洞中发现了一盏内有灯神的神灯
Aladdin finds a lamp containing a genie in a cave.
很多人认为这个洞
Many people believe this cave
正是所罗门王的陵寝
was actually King Solomon's tomb,
而它极有可能位于
which is most likely located
叙利亚和土耳其边境"
near the border of Syria and Turkey."
伙计们  知道这意味着什么吗
You guys, you know what this means?
别啊
Oh, please, no.
拜托  钱  保时捷
Come on. The money, the Porsche.
是拉斯许的愿望  他的愿望成真了
Lars wished for them, and his wishes were granted...
来了
And here we go.
灯神实现了他的愿望
...by a genie!
拉斯找到了阿拉丁神灯
Lars found Aladdin's lamp!
太好了  谢谢  戴安
Perfect! Thank you, Diane.
-伙计们  -嗯
- Guys? - Yeah?
看啊
Look at this.
拉斯公寓里这些关于《一千零一夜》的书
These books from Lars' apartment on "1001 Arabian Nights,"
上面都有手写笔记
they all have handwritten notes in them.
这个还画了地图
This one has... maps drawn in it.
这本里夹着关于所罗门王墓葬地的理论
This one has his theories of where King Solomon is buried.
这些书是他的调研
These books were his research that he used
再加上他作为声纳工程师的技术
in conjunction with his skills as a sonar engineer
加起来就找到了所罗门王的陵寝
to unearth King Solomon's tomb...
是啊  这我们同意
Yeah, we're with you on that.
于是他找到了内有灯神的神灯
...and find the magical lamp with the genie in it.
这里我们就不同意了  卡塞尔
That's where you lose us, Castle.
那盏灯唯一的神奇之处
The only thing magical about that lamp
在于私人收藏家会为其支付的
is the millions of dollars that private collectors
数百万美元
are willing to pay for it.
得了  卡塞尔
Come on, Castle.
你不是真的相信灯神吧
you don't really believe in genies, do you?
我相信  除非我听到拉斯得到那么多钱
I believethat until I hear a more viable theory
更合理的理论
as to where Lars got all that money
这就是我的最佳理论了
that this is the best theory I've got.
那么你的最佳解释是一个灯神
So, a genie is your best explanation?
而不是拉斯在土耳其卖掉了其中一个物件
Not that Lars sold one of the items in Turkey
然后又把剩余的再偷运回来
before smuggling the rest back here?
好吧  这个理论还挺不错
Okay, it's a... pretty good theory.
或是拉斯背叛了搭档
Or that Lars double-crossed his partner,
现金大概就是这么来的
and that's probably where all the cash came from.
好吧  这个理论也不错
Fine. That's a good theory, too.
不不  这很棒
No, no, no. That's -- That's better than good.
这解释了他为什么被折磨
It explains why the killer tortured him.
如果凶手是他的搭档  他肯定想
If it was his partner, then he would've wanted
知道剩下的古董去哪了
to find out what happened to the antiquities.
我们会去调查拉斯在土耳其期间的活动
We'll look into Lars' time in Turkey,
看能不能挖掘到他和搭档之间的联系
see if we can dig up a connection to his partner.
好
Okay.
我赌是拍下那些照片的人
My money -- it's whoever took those pictures. Yeah.
那是什么
What do you got there?
写这本书的女人  玛丽昂·贝克博士
The woman who wrote this book, Dr. Marion Baker,
她是一名中东文学教授
she's a professor of Middle Eastern literature
在哈德逊大学任教
at Hudson University.
我们该去找她谈
We should go talk to her.
对神灯有更多了解
Knowing more about the lamp
能帮我们查清拉斯为什么因此招来杀身之祸
will help us figure out why Lars was killed for it.
你就是想去了解灯神和许愿的事
You just want to find out more about genies and wishes.
是啊
Well, yeah.
去吧  去见贝克博士吧
Fine, go ahead. Meet with Dr. Baker.
或许她能让你认清现实
Maybe she can talk some sense into you.
你的愿望是我的命令
Your wish is my command.
化作烟
Smoke!
他消失了
And he's gone.
好吧  我真走了
Okay, now I'm gone.
天啊
Oh...my...
所罗门王的陵寝  真了不起
King Solomon's tomb. Remarkable.
这可能是这五十年来最了不起的发现了
It's arguably the greatest discovery in the last 50 years.
贝克博士  这是我需要你专长的地方了
Now, this, Dr. Baker, is what I need your expertise with.
好的
Certainly.
看那凹槽
Oh, you see these grooves.
这表明灯是用轮子轧制的
They indicate it was a wheel-made lamp
而不是铸造的  那是在40年代...
versus the mold-based ones that became so popular in the '40s --
引人入胜  博士  但能不能快进到
Uh, fascinating, Doctor, but can you skip ahead
所罗门王往里面封印了灯神的部分
to the part where King Solomon seals a genie inside of it?
是西德尼叫你这么做的吗
Did Sidney put you up to this?
西德尼是谁
Who's Sidney?
终身教授职位被我顶下去的二货
The schmuck I beat out for tenure.
贝克博士  我不认识西德尼
Dr. Baker, I do not know Sidney.
这不是玩笑  我很认真的
This is not a joke. I am very serious.
但你一副真相信灯神的样子
But you're acting as if you believe in genies.
博士  这不是演戏
Doctor, it's not an act.
阿拉丁神灯的故事不过是
Well, the story of "Aladdin and the Magic Lamp"
爱情隐喻而已
is a romantic metaphor, nothing more.
当然了  但如果  仅仅是如果
Of course, but what if -- and I -- and I'm only saying
如果灯神的故事是有现实依据的呢
what if the legend of genies were based in fact?
希望不会  灯神是很可怕的
Well, I certainly hope it isn't. Genies are frightful creatures.
你是说他们不是活泼的60年代主妇
You're saying they're not cheery '60s housewives
或是高唱卡通歌曲吗
or singing blue cartoons?
这么说吧
I'll put it to you like this.
在阿拉伯语中  灯神和"恶魔"
In Arabic, they use the same word for "Demon"
是同一个词
as they do for "Genie."
他们是危险  反复无常的骗子
They're dangerous, capricious tricksters
随着清风来去无踪
who appear and disappear in gentle breezes
要么化作烟尘来去
or a whirlwind of dust.
如果神灯主人的愿望
Now, what if the master of the lamp is killed
实现前就被杀了呢
before the wishes are granted?
那么没有主人的灯神
Well, then the masterless genie
会与神灯分开
would be separated from its lamp.
就像日本的浪人武士吗
Like a Japanese ronin samurai?
是啊  但灯神将
Exactly, but the genie would be forced
只能四处游荡  直到有新的主人摸灯
to wander the earth until a new master rubs the lamp.
再跟我说说  贝克博士
Tell me more, Dr. Baker.
好啊  仅需19.95美元
Oh, sure -- for the low, low price of $19.95.
去买我的书吧
Buy my book.
你的故事可不是免费讲的  卡塞尔先生
You don't give your stories away for free, Mr. Castle,
我也是
and neither do I.
好了  失陪  我还得去上课
So, if, uh, you'll excuse me, I have a class to teach.
-谢谢  -谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
老爸  你怎么想的
Dad, what are you thinking?
拉斯发现了灯
Lars found the lamp,
显然  他摸了灯
and, clearly, he rubbed it,
这样他就是灯神的主人了  是吧
but that makes him the genie's master, right?
但如果之后都再没人摸过灯
But if no one has rubbed the lamp since
接着又被我找到了
and I were to discover it...
那我就是灯神的新主人了
then that would make me the genie's new master.
好吧
Okay.
就算这都是真的
Let's just pretend that all this is real.
你知道如果拉斯是灯神的主人
You do realize that if Lars was the genie's master,
那么他的下场可不太好
it didn't work out so well for him in the end.
你什么意思
What are you saying?
许愿时要谨慎
Be careful what you wish for.
你的愿望或许会成真
It just might come true.
在这件事上  你可能会因此招来杀身之祸
And in this case, it might just get you killed.
我现在真希望有个灯神
I could really use a genie right now.
我会许愿我的孩子已经降生
I would wish that my kid was already born
每晚都能安然入睡
and sleeping through the night.
哥们  你当爹后变得好无趣
Bro, fatherhood has made you so damn boring.
如果我可以许愿
If I had a wish,
我会许愿成为全世界最棒的综合格斗拳手
I'd use it to become the top MMA fighter in the world
每晚都能带一个不同的性感小妞回家
and take home a different hot chick every single night.
我转念一想
Okay, now that I think about it...
我会许愿
I would wish...
我可以做个百老汇明星
that I could be a Broadway star.
在满场的观众面前扮演冉·阿让
Play Jean Valjean in front of sold-out crowds,
赢下一堆托尼奖
win a bunch of Tonys.
你要许愿穿紧身衣
You'd wish to wear tights
唱歌为生吗
and sing show tunes for a living?
你要许愿穿三角裤
You'd wish to wear Speedos
跟浑身大汗的男人摔跤为生吗
and grapple sweaty men for a living?
每晚能换个性感小妞带回家
And hook up with a different hot chick every night.
-别忘了这部分  -知道我想许什么愿吗
- Don't forget that part. - You know what I wish?
我的警探
That my detectives would
能好好干活儿为生
actually get some work done for a living.
你们去梦想岛时
While the two of you were on Fantasy Island,
我找到了线索
I found a lead.
麦克·哈林
Mike Harlin.
切萨皮克能源公司的地表钻工
He's a surface driller for Chesapeake Energy.
跟拉斯原是同公司同事
That is the same company that Lars worked for.
他跟拉斯搭了同一班
He was also on the same plane
飞机从土耳其飞回纽约
as Lars from Turkey to New York.
他肯定是拉斯的搭档
He's got to be Lars' partner.
我定位了他的手机  已经断线了
I pinged his cellphone. It's disconnected.
他要跑
He's making a run for it.
如果他靠折磨拉斯
And if he tortured the location
问出了古董的位置
of the antiquities out of Lars...
那么他很可能
Then there's a good chance
要去拿走古董  并永远逃脱
that he's gonna grab them and try to disappear for good.
阿丽克西斯
Alexis?
你
You.
你闯进了我办公室
You broke into my office?
不  是红发妞放我进来的
No, the redhead let me in.
叫我在里面等
Said I could wait inside.
你翻了我的桌子
You went through my desk.
找笔给你写字条
To look for a pen to write you a note.
你真的好不相信人啊
Wow, you are a very distrusting person.
是啊  有人对我撒谎时我就会这样
Yes, I get that way when I'm lied to.
我不知道你是谁
Now, I don't know who you are,
但你绝对不是拉斯的邻居
but you sure as hell are not Lars' neighbor.
我要报警了
I'm calling the police.
如果你报警  我就离开
If you do, I'm out that door.
你也无法知道我可以是多么厉害的同盟了
And you'll never know how powerful of an ally I can be.
好  给你一分钟说服我  说吧
All right, you got one minute to convince me. Go.
我叫琳赛·蒂里昂
My name is Lindsay Dillon.
我是名记者  在调查
I'm a journalist researching a story
古董掠夺的事
about looted antiquities.
土耳其一名线人透露
A source in Turkey hinted
拉斯可能找到了所罗门王的陵寝
that Lars may have discovered King Solomon's tomb,
所以我就决定盯着他
so I decided to keep tabs on him.
所以才听到了他跟前男友之间的争吵
That's when I overheard the fight he had with his ex-boyfriend.
为什么不报警  为什么撒谎
So, why not tell the police? Why lie?
因为如果有人死了
Because when you've got a dead body,
古董被盗的新闻
a story about stolen relics
从没人在乎
turns from a back-page snoozer
转眼就变成了头版头条
to a front-page lead just like that.
虽然我想在
And though I wanted to be helpful
你们的凶杀案调查中帮忙
to your murder investigation --
但如果你正式作证
If you made an official statement,
记者们都会得知你的报道
every reporter would hear about your story,
你就不能做独家了
and you'd lose your exclusive.
瞧  我就知道你能理解
See? I knew you'd get it.
这也不是你闯进我办公室的原因
That doesn't explain why you broke into my office un...
除非你有了新线索
Unless you have another lead.
我们都是作家
We're both writers.
我们彼此帮助吧
Let's help each other out.
但你得把我当做匿名线人
Only you've got to keep me as your anonymous source.
-可以吗  -可以
- Deal? - Deal.
你知道什么
What do you got?
拉斯在跟一个叫麦克·哈林的人合作
Lars was working with a guy named Mike Harlin.
我们已经知道他了  但他失踪了
Yeah, we know about him already, but he's missing,
除非你知道他躲在哪
unless you know where he's been hiding?
不  但我知道
No. But I do know
哈林在土耳其期间用了假名
that Harlin used an alias while in Turkey.
阿尔·艾登
Al Aiden.
这很棒
This is great.
我要上报
I'm gonna call this in.
阿尔·艾登
Al Aiden.
阿拉丁
Aladdin!
真逗
Yeah, that's cute.
我有线索给你
Hey, I have a lead for you.
是...
It's the -- Uh...
稍等
hang on a second.
拦住那女人
Stop that woman.
什么女人
What woman?
那个金发女  那个刚刚
T-The blonde woman. The woman who just...
她怎么从你身边过去的
How did she get past you?
警监  前台证实阿尔·艾登
Yeah, Cap, front desk confirmed an Al Aiden
今早入住了57号房间
checked into room 57 this morning.
我们正在往那边走
We're on our way to the room now.
麦克·哈林
Mike Harlin?
纽约警局
NYPD!
离窗户远点
Hey, away from the window now!
-好吧  -马上跪下
- Okay! Okay! - Get on your knees right now!
好的  冷静
Okay! Okay. Chill, man.
在脑后交叉双手
Interlace your fingers behind your head.
好
All right.
我就知道她会让你们找到我
I knew she'd lead you to me.
谁  你指谁
Who? What are you talking about?
灯神啊
The genie, man!
她想要我的命
She's out to get me.
灯神是邪恶的
Genies are evil.
他们的愿望只能带来痛苦
And their wishes bring about nothing but misery.
我明白是怎么回事了
I see what's happening here.
那个浪人灯神生哈林的气
The, uh, wandering ronin genie is angry with Harlin
因为他杀了其主人
for killing her master.
所以她不让他找到神灯
That's why she prevented him from finding the lamp.
卡塞尔  此人要么是有妄想
Yeah, Castle, the man is either delusional
要么是在为荒唐的
or he's laying the groundwork
精神失常辩护打基础
for some B.S. insanity plea.
你是怎么回事
What's your excuse?
我们来谈一下拉斯吧
Let's talk about Lars
还有你是怎么用刀砍掉他的头的
and how you chopped his head off with a sword.
不不不  我可没杀他
No, no, no, no, no. I didn't kill him.
好吧  他被杀的时候
Okay, I was at my mom's birthday party
我在参加我妈妈的生日派对
when he got murdered.
伙计  不信你去查
Man, check it out!
我敢肯定砍了拉斯头的那个人
I'm sure whoever took Lars' head off
马上就会来杀我了
is coming for mine next.
是吗  为什么
Really? Why is that?
我知道的太多了
I know too much.
我和拉斯  我们是在土耳其工作认识的
Me and Lars, we met on the job in Turkey.
好吧
Okay?
有一天
And then one day...
在进行完声呐搜索油槽后  拉斯过来找我
after a sonar search for oil pockets, Lars came to me.
他但是非常激动
He was all excited.
因为他发现了所罗门王的墓穴位置
Because he found the location of King Solomon's tomb,
然后你用你的挖掘本领
and you use your skills as an excavator
帮他把墓挖了出来
to help him dig it out.
不不  没那么简单
No, no, it wasn't that easy.
我们需要钱才能安全地完成这工作
We needed money to do it safely, okay?
所以拉斯去找了个人
So Lars, he found some guy.
他给我们每个人二十五万现金干这活
He offered us 250Ks each in cash to do the dig.
条件就是  如果我们找到了什么
The catch was, if we found something,
拉斯就要把东西运给这个人
well, Lars had to ship it to the guy
他在纽约
who's here in New York.
那这个金主是谁
Okay, so, who is this financier?
我不知道
I don't know.
给钱那么多
Look, the money was too good,
所以我什么都没问
so I didn't ask any questions.
不过我也希望我问了  因为打开那墓穴
I-I-I wish I did, though, 'cause opening that tomb
是我们做过的最糟糕的事了
was the worst thing that had happened to us.
自从我们拿走那盏灯后
I mean the moment we took that lamp,
灯神就开始复仇了  伙计
that genie unleased its vengeance, man.
你不是想让我们相信
You can't honestly be trying to tell us
你看到了一个灯神吧
that you saw a genie.
不  但是灯神可以选择
No, but genies can choose to appear
让谁看到或者不让谁看到
or not to appear to anyone they want.
真的
That's true.
贝克教授就是这么跟我说的
Professor Baker told me that,
而且她是个博士  所以
and she's a doctor, so...
二位  以前我也不相信有灯神  好吧
Look, guys, I didn't believe in genies, either, okay?
直到我的生活崩溃之后
Until my life fell apart.
我的女朋友跟我的室友上床了
I found my girlfriend in bed with my roommate,
然后我就跟我妈妈住到了一起
and then I stayed with my mom,
可我妈妈不小心扔掉了我的背包
and my mom accidentally threw out the duffel bag
里面装着那二十五万块钱
with my 250 G's!
我想起这些事情
You know, and when I think that things,
我觉得我已经不能再倒霉了
they -- they can't get any worse,
可拉斯的头被砍掉了
I found out that Lars got his head lopped off,
现在那个灯神  那个可怕邪恶的灯神
and now that genie -- that crazy, evil genie --
就要来杀我了  我很清楚
is after me, man! I know it!
好了  哈林  你还是
Okay, Harlin, I'm gonna have to
清醒一下吧
get you off the crazy train
别这么疯了
that you're riding on right now.
是的  我们知道送货的时候出了问题
Yeah, we know that the shipment got screwed up
而且你怀疑拉斯坑了你
and -- and you suspected that Lars double-crossed you.
什么  没有
What? No.
没有  拉斯没有坑我
No, Lars did not double-cross me.
他是被运货的人坑了
He got double-crossed by the shipper.
准确来说  是走私贩
Okay, well, really, the smuggler.
你不可能拿着价值连城的文物过海关
You can't just walk past customs with priceless relics
同时又不引起别人的怀疑  对吧
and expect no one to notice, right?
所以  拉斯在土耳其雇了一个人
So, Lars hired a guy back in Turkey
把东西运回来吗
to ship the items back?
-他叫什么名字  -我不知道
- What was his name? - I don't know.
但我知道  等等
I do know. Hold on.
但我  我知道
I do -- I do know
他骗了那个送货的人  好吧
that he lied to the shipper, okay?
他跟他说只是些开采设备
He told him it was just mining equipment.
可不走运的是  他的一个手下
The only thing was that one from his crew
撬开了箱子  发现了里面的文物
jimmied the crate and, found the artifacts.
我猜一下  送货的人提高价码了
Let me guess. The shipper started seeing dollar signs?
是的  他要四十万  还是现金
Yeah, and then he demanded 400 grand -- in cash
才会发货
just to release the shipment.
这就解释了我们在拉斯保险箱里
That explains the cash that we found
发现的那些钱
in Lars' safe-deposit box.
是的  可是拉斯是怎么弄到
Right, but how the hell did Lars get his hands on
四十万块钱的呢
400,000 bucks?
别  别说是他许愿得到的
Uh, don't -- don't say that he wished for it.
他可能是从金主那拿到的
He probably got the money from the financier.
可是有一件事说不通
But -- but the one thing that doesn't make sense is,
如果拉斯已经拿到了这笔钱
if Lars already had the extortion money,
那为什么送货的人还要杀了他呢
then why did the shipper kill him?
别说
Uh, don't --
别说这是想掌控灯神
do not say that it was to gain control of the genie.
我没打算那么说
I wasn't gonna.
好吧  我是想这么说
Okay, I was.
不过还有另一种可能
But there is another possibility.
可能送货的人自己把宝藏留下了
Maybe the shipper kept the treasure for himself.
那为什么要折磨拉斯呢
Well, then why torture Lars?
如果他已经拿到文物的话
I mean, what information could he possibly want
那他想要知道什么消息呢
if he already had the artifacts?
各位  查到金主是谁了吗
Hey, guys, any leads on who the financier is?
没有  雇拉斯和哈林盗墓的这个人
No. Whoever paid for Lars' and Harlin's tomb raiding
把踪迹隐藏得很好
made sure to cover their tracks.
哈林的不在场证据证实了
Well, Harlin's alibi checked out.
也就是说这位神秘的送货人
Which means that this mystery shipper
是我们的首要嫌疑人
is our prime suspect.
如果他当时敲诈了拉斯
If he was extorting Lars,
那他就有很大的动机杀他
he'd have plenty of motive for murder.
好吧  去海关那查一下
Okay, check in with customs.
把上周所有
Let's get a list of all of the ships
从土耳其来的船列一份名单
that have come in from Turkey in the last week.
如果我们能查到文物的下落
If we can track down those antiquities,
应该就能找到凶手了
that should lead us to the killer.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
你还好吗
Hey, are you okay?
不好  我一直再查
No. I've been doing some digging
那位神秘的金发女郎
into that mystery blonde.
你是说那个记者
You mean the reporter?
她既不是记者  也不是拉斯的邻居
She is no more a reporter than she was Lars' neighbor.
什么  她又骗了你一次
What? She lied to you again?
这才是真正的琳赛·蒂里昂
This is the real Lindsay Dillon,
住在塔拉哈西的65岁黑人老太太
a 65-year-old black woman living in Tallahassee.
那这个金发女郎有啥企图
Oh. So, what's this blonde's angle?
我也想知道
I wish I knew.
她一边说谎
She lies out of one side of her mouth,
却一边又帮忙查案
helps with the investigation out of the other.
这说不通啊
It just doesn't make any sense.
就目前我们所知道的
Well, I mean, for all we know,
她可能是和凶手一伙的
she could be working with the killer,
想要误导我们的调查方向
trying to steer us in the wrong direction.
两次她都从我面前消失了
Twice, she just vanished on me.
都从我面前消失了
Vanished on me.
卡塞尔
Castle?
来去自如
Appearing and disappearing at will,
既骗我又帮我
being both deceptive and helpful?
那个神秘的金发女郎就是拉斯的灯神
The mystery blonde is Lars' Ronin Genie,
在地球上游荡  等待别人找到她的神灯
wandering the earth, waiting for someone to find her lamp.
她选择让我看见她
She's chosen to appear to me.
行了  别喝了
That's it. I'm cutting you off.
不  她已经给我线索了  贝克特
No. She's -- She's given me clues, Beckett.
她希望我找到神灯
She wants me to find the lamp.
我想她希望我成为她的新主人
I think she wants me to be her new master.
你觉得我怎么认为
And you know what I think?
下次你再看到她的时候得叫上我
You need to call me the next time you see her
这样我才能审问她
so I can question her.
我得去想一个愿望清单
I got to come up with a wish list.
天哪  我有好多愿望
Oh, my God. I have so many!
我怎么才能把它减少到三个呢
How am I gonna whittle it down to three?!
有意思  我只有一个愿望
That's funny. I just have one.
什么愿望
What's that?
我希望我的男人能不要再谈
That my man would stop talking about
成为某个金发女郎的主人
being some skeezy blonde's master
而开始考虑
and would start talking about taking...
和他的妻子去睡觉
...his wife to bed.
好啊
Oh, well...
我不需要灯神
I don't need a genie...
来实现这个愿望
to grant that wish.
嘿  头儿  我们复核了哈林说的
Yo, hey, Cap, so, we cross-checked customs' records
那天的海关记录
with the date that Harlin said
拉斯把古董装上船了
Lars shipped the antiquities.
当天有一条船在伊斯坦布尔出港了
One ship left port that day in Istanbul,
而这条船在纽约卸下的唯一的货物
and the only cargo that it dropped off in New York
寄给了这个人  约瑞克·塞曾
was a shipment to this man, Yuruk Sezen.
他在苏豪区的一家店面里经营进口地毯的生意
He runs a rug-import business with a storefront in SoHo.
很明显  他就是我们找的托运人
So, obviously, he's our shipper.
是啊  我们现在就去那儿
Yeah, we're headed there now.
希望那些古董还在他那儿
Hopefully, he still has the antiquities.
包括  神灯
Including the, uh, magic lamp.
伙计们
Uh, guys, guys?
如果你们找到了那盏灯而卡塞尔不在场
If you find that lamp and Castle's not there,
那我的耳根就别想清净了
I'm never gonna hear the end of it.
那我们叫他和我们在那汇合
We'll have him meet us there.
好  还有  你们能
Okay, great. Ooh, can you just --
你们能保证让他第一个擦那盏灯吗
can you make sure that he gets dibs
拜托了
on the first rub, please?
太好了  谢谢  我欠你们个人情
Good. Thanks. I owe you.
不敢相信我竟然说了那些话
Can't believe I said that.
纽约警局
NYPD!
有人吗
Are you in here?!
安全
Clear.
我这里安全
I'm clear.
安全
Clear.
看样子约瑞克已经跑了
Looks like Yuruk skipped town.
你在拿毯子做什么
Why are you playing with the carpets?
我在检查它们是不是魔毯  仔细想想吧
I'm checking if they're magic. Think about it.
伙计们
Guys?
这张毯子在流血
This carpet's bleeding.
似曾相识啊
Deja-vu.
看看这些瘀伤
Check out these bruises,
跟拉斯身上的一样
just like Lars'.
胸上  腰上  脚踝上都有胶带
Duct tape on his chest, wrists, and ankles.
有人一定也把他绑起来了
Someone must have tied him up, too.
所以除了彻底分离的头
So, apart from the fully detached head,
手法和拉斯一样  折磨然后杀死
the M.O.'s identical to Lars -- tortured, then killed.
显然  约瑞克不是我们的凶手
Well, clearly, Yuruk's not our killer.
真正的凶手一定是通过折磨拉斯
Well, the true killer must have
来找到约瑞克的
tortured Lars to get to Yuruk.
然后折磨约瑞克来找到那些失窃的古董
Then tortured Yuruk to get to those stolen antiquities.
尸体还是热的  凶手刚刚离开这里
This body's still warm. The killer was just here.
卡塞尔  去叫后援
Castle, go call for backup.
-去前门等他们  - 好
- Wait for them out front. - Right.
嘿  贝克特  对
Hey, Beckett. Yeah.
不  他们在在守着后门
No, right now, they're securing the back.
好的  我们会在的
All right. We'll be here.
灯神
The genie.
那是灯神
It's the genie.
我就知道是你
I knew it was you!
你  你不是我以为的那个人
You -- You are not who I thought you were.
抱歉  祝你今天愉快
I'm so sorry. Have a lovely day.
我的后背
Ah, my back.
你得把那个还给我
I'm gonna need that back.
当然  让我先掸一下土
Sure. Let me just dust it off.
别碰
Uh, ah-ah, hands!
特维斯  快一点  我们有同伴了
Travis, hurry it up! We've got company!
-你是谁  -小人物
- Who the hell are you? - Nobody.
-你在这做什么  -什么也不做
- What are you doing here? - Nothing.
你是个小人物在这什么也不做
So you're nobody doing nothing?
很高兴认识你  我
Pleased to meet you. I...
很乐意跟你聊天  但你看上去很忙
would love to chat, but, uh, you are obviously busy
忙于某些合法的事情
in whatever clearly legal endeavor you're engaged in.
-你是警察吗  -不  不是警察
- Are you a cop? - No, no, not a cop.
很好
Good.
别  别  如果  如果我是个警察呢
Whoa, whoa, whoa. What if -- What if I was a cop?
一样  我都要杀了你
Either way, I'm gonna kill you.
你向我开枪  我就把这个摔了
You shoot me, I drop this,
它就会碎成很多块了
and it breaks into a million pieces.
没关系  我还有一堆呢
It's okay. I've got a dozen more.
但它们都有灯神吗
But do they have a genie?
你多大了  五岁吗
What are you, 5 years old?
抱歉  老兄  我得做我该做的事了
I'm sorry, pal. I got to do what I got to do.
我真的希望你不要做
I really wish you wouldn't!
你真是一个灯神
You are a genie!
快跑
Come on.
我  神灯
I -- The lamp!
-但是你的神灯  那是你的  -别管它了
- But your lamp! It's yours! - Leave it!
你就不能让我们坐在毯子上飞出去吗
Couldn't you have just flown us out of there on a carpet?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你不能让毯子飞吗
You can't make carpets fly?
你能吗
Can you?
我又不是灯神
I'm not a genie.
我也不是
Neither am I.
是啊  灯神会这么说
Yeah, something a genie would say
因为他们是骗子和无赖
because they're liars and tricksters.
按你这么说
By that logic,
任何骗子都可能是灯神
any liar could be a genie.
我们现在抓住你了  你哪儿也去不了了
Well, we've caught you now, and you're not going anywhere.
警察们就在那边
The cops are right over there.
所以你得告诉我们你知道的一切
And you're gonna tell us everything you know.
有没有搞错啊
Come on!
等我们围住那个区域时
When we put the net over the neighborhood,
卡车和财宝都消失不见了
the truck and the treasure were gone,
因为你没能记下车牌号
and because you didn't get a license plate,
我们找到他们的希望很小
we have little chance of finding them.
一切发生的太快了
It all happened so fast.
噢  但你却有时间
Oh, right, and yet you did have time
偷偷靠近神灯  检查神灯
to "Creep over to the lamp, examine it,
拿着它面对枪口  擦神灯
get held at gunpoint, rub the lamp,
对着神灯许愿  让灯神在一阵烟雾里出现
make a wish upon the lamp, and have a genie appear
再用木板把女暴徒打晕
in a puff of smoke and knock the 'woman thug' over the head with a 2x4."
你忘记说那里又黑尘土又多了
You forgot the part where it was dark and super dusty.
卡塞尔  你很幸运
Castle, you're just lucky
蕾妮从约瑞克的尸体上提取到了DNA
that Lanie was able to pull DNA off Yuruk's body.
她找到匹配了吗
Did she manage to get a match?
不  但是她能确定
No, but she was able
凶手是个女性
to determine that the killer was a female.
很可能是那个拿枪指着我的女人
Most likely the woman holding me at gunpoint.
或者是你那位神奇的金发灯神
Or your magical, blond genie.
只有卡塞尔能看见的那位
The one only Castle's seen.
等等  你们俩都不相信我吗
Wait a minute. So, neither of you believe me?
不  哥们  我确实相信你
Oh, no, bro, I-I do believe you.
实际上根据你的描述
I actually -- I was able to I.D. the genie
我查到了那个灯神的身份
based on your description.
干得漂亮
Good work.
笑就笑吧  我还有两个愿望没许呢
Laugh it up, you guys. I still have two wishes left.
我不介意拿它们来干点坏事
I'm not above using them for evil.
-爸爸  -阿丽克西斯
- Dad? - Ah, Alexis.
很好  太棒了
Good, great.
快告诉他俩我相信灯神不是因为我疯了
Tell these guys am I not crazy for believing in a genie.
在你回答之前你要记住  有六个月的时间
And before you answer, remember, I spent six months
我都多做了一份午餐给你想象中的朋友
making an extra lunch for your imaginary friend.
-真的吗  -那时我才七岁  但你也没疯
- Really? - Guys, I was 7, but you're not crazy.
那位神秘的金发女郎是真实存在的
The mystery blonde is real.
太感谢你了
Thank you!
但她不是灯神
But she's not a genie.
她的名字叫吉妮维芙·萨顿
Her name is Genevieve Sutton.
她在第二大道有一个服务处
She has an office on Second Avenue.
她被列为是个安全顾问
She's listed as a security consultant.
听起来像个清道夫
A fixer by the sound of it.
你怎么找到这些信息的  阿丽克西斯
Now, how did you get this info, Alexis?
我爸走之后  我在他桌子上找到了指纹
Well, after Dad left, I dusted his desk for prints.
让海莉帮了我点小忙
Got a little help from Hayley,
她在车管所的数据库了搜索了一下  看吧
who ran them through the DMV database, and voil?
这么说她不是灯神
So she's not a genie?
抱歉
Sorry.
"吉妮"是吉妮维芙的简称吉妮
Genevieve is short for "Genie."
说真的  如果她能帮人实现愿望
I-I mean, seriously, if she can grant wishes,
弄一个驾驶证出来也很容易
a-a-a driver's license, that would be a piece of cake.
但一个灯神怎么会这么做
but why would a genie want to do that?
说真的  谁在乎呀
Oh, seriously, who cares?
卡塞尔的过家家结束了
Make-believe time with Castle is over.
我们会把吉妮维芙带来  找出真相
We're gonna bring in Genevieve and find out the real story.
有人想吃冰淇淋吗
Someone need some ice cream?
我
Me.
卡塞尔  什么...
Castle, what --
你也许把大家都骗过去了  但除了我
You may have everyone else fooled, but not me.
卡塞尔  让我进去
Castle, let me in.
我是你的主人
I am your master.
我命令你告诉我真相
I command you to tell me the truth.
-卡塞尔  -你到底是不是灯神
- Castle! - Are you a genie or not?
你能让她进来吗
Can you let her in?
因为你把我搞得好毛骨悚然
Because you're seriously weirding me out.
我就当你说的是有可能
I'm gonna take that as a maybe.
对不起
I would apologize,
但你用不着担心他的举动
but his behavior is the least of your worries.
你被指控犯有两起谋杀案
You are accused of two homicides
并与价值几百万的古董盗窃
and connected to the theft and trafficking
以及非法交易有关
of millions of dollars in antiquities,
所以你最好的选择就是开口
so your best bet is to start talking.
听着  我没有杀害任何人
Look, I didn't kill anyone, and I was trying
我在尽力不让那些文物落入恶人之手
to keep the relics from falling into the wrong hands.
我本来能成功的  要是我没有出手救你这位
And I would've, too, if I hadn't had to save your...
有现实障碍的丈夫的话
reality-challenged husband.
我更喜欢幻想争辩这个词
I prefer fantasy-augmented.
你说的"恶人之手"是什么意思
Uh, what do you mean by "Wrong hands"?
拉斯被雇去发掘那些古董
Lars was hired to excavate the antiquities
是为了保护它们
in order to protect them.
被谁雇去
Hired by who?
一位匿名捐助者  我们就称他X先生吧
An anonymous benefactor. Let's call him Mr. X.
叙利亚战争有波及土耳其的危险
With the Syrian conflict threatening to spill over into Turkey,
X先生很担心所罗门的墓会被破坏
Mr. X became concerned that Solomon's tomb would be destroyed
甚至被洗劫  文物被卖为恐怖活动提供资金
or worse, looted and the relics sold to fund terrorism.
你是怎么知道这一切的
And you know all of this how?
X先生找到了我的服务为了确保
Mr. X retained my services in order to ensure
拉斯能从约瑞克那追回这些文物
Lars recovered the artifacts from Yuruk.
但拉斯却死了
But instead, Lars ended up dead.
很不幸
Unfortunately.
拉斯被害那晚
The night that Lars was murdered,
我因为一条错误的线索被调离了
I was pulled away on a false lead.
当我回来时  到处都是警察
When I got back, the cops were everywhere.
所以我就盯上了卡塞尔先生
So I targeted Mr. Castle
想借助他了解警察都知道些什么
as a way to learn what the police knew.
我想你并没有获得那辆卡车的牌照
I don't suppose you got the license plate of that truck
当你在救我的时候
as you were...saving me?
是没有
No.
但我在救你之前就有了
But I did before I saved you.
州警察刚找到了那辆卡车
State police just found the truck.
我们接入了拉伊外一个休息站的实时动态
We're tapped into a live feed from a rest stop outside of Rye.
我们查到了那辆卡车
We've got eyes on the truck.
证实有车上有人吗
Do you have confirmation of passengers?
确定  有两名乘客  一男一女
Affirmative. Two passengers -- male and female,
符合对嫌疑犯的描述
fitting the descriptions of the suspects.
宝贝  对不起  现在真不是通电话的时候
Oh, hey, babe. Sorry, It's not really a good time right now.
什么
What?
好  好  好  我马上过来
Uh, yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah, I-I will be right there.
大家
Um, hey, guys...
珍妮要生了
Jenny's having the baby.
太棒了  兄弟
That's awesome, man.
太棒了  快去吧
Yeah, that's great! Go, go!
-有事打电话  兄弟  -好的
- Call me, bro. - Yeah!
等等  嫌疑人要下车了
Hold on. Suspects are exiting the truck.
我们要行动吗
Do we have a green light?
确定
Affirmative.
纽约警局  趴下  有枪
NYPD! Get down! Guns, guns!
警监  现在是什么情况
Captain, what's your status?
男性嫌疑人被击倒  医护人员正在抢救
Male suspect is down. Medic is treating him now.
我们抓捕到女性嫌疑人
We have the female suspect in custody.
我是贝克特警监  车上有发现什么吗
This is Captain Beckett. Is there anything in that truck?
有  有是十一个板条箱
Affirmative. I count 11 crates.
吉妮维芙说应该有十二个
Genevieve said that there would be 12.
我想我知道哪个箱子不在了
I bet I know which crate is missing.
那个灯在哪里  菲比
Where's the lamp, Phoebe?
在这你只有一个机会
You've got one chance to help yourself here.
我们知道你没有杀害约瑞克
Now, we know you didn't kill Yuruk.
交通监控显示当他被害时
Traffic cams put you and the truck
你还有那辆车在城市的另一边
on the other side of the city when he was murdered.
但你跟特维斯也逃不了成为雇佣同伙事实
And that makes you and Travis little more than the hired help.
为了你自己还是开口比较好
So I'd do myself a favor and start talking,
就从你把那盏灯送去给谁开始吧
beginning with who you delivered the lamp to.
我也许是雇佣同伙  但我不是叛徒
I might be hired help, but I ain't no rat.
我需要律师
I want a lawyer.
我知道我的权利
I know my rights.
DNA显示凶手是一名女性
DNA confirms that our killer's a woman
但肯定是一个有着资源还有关系的人
but someone with resources and connections,
不是这种小人
not this flunky.
一个认识拉斯的凶手  一个女人
A killer who knew Lars, a woman who...
会冒着失去整批货物的风险
would risk losing the entire shipment
就为了终极的战利品  那盏灯
for the ultimate prize -- the lamp.
我知道有个人能带我们找到真相
And I know just the person to lead us to it.
贝克博士  再次感谢你能来
Dr. Baker, thank you again for coming to see us.
当你告诉我你找到了阿拉丁的灯神
Well, how could I resist
我怎么能拒绝呢
when you told me you found the genie from Aladdin's lamp?
那是个小小的善意的谎言
That was a little bit of a white lie.
是这样  我们查看了一下
Yeah, see, we were looking back
拉斯在哥伦比亚的学校记录
over Lars' school records from Columbia.
发现他几年前在哈德逊大学
It turns out he actually audited a class of yours
旁听过一节你的课
at Hudson University a few years back.
我每年都有很多新生
I have hundreds of students every year.
没法记住所有人
I'm afraid I can't remember all of them.
那就奇怪了  你的助教记得你和拉斯
That's strange. Your T.A. remembers that you and Lars
在你上班时间会定期会面
would meet regularly during your office hours.
事实上  他说拉斯从土耳其回来的那天早上
In fact, he said that you guys met the morning
你们还见面了呢
that Lars returned from Turkey.
拉斯肯定也了解你对神灯的研究成果
Now, Lars, I'm sure, shared the discovery of the lamp with you,
他知道你比任何人都更能领会神灯的价值
knowing that you of all people would appreciate its value,
但他却万没料到你对他产生了职业嫉妒
but what he wasn't counting on was your professional jealousy.
我为什么要嫉妒
Why on earth would I be jealous?
你寻找所罗门国王的墓穴已经15年了
You've been searching for King Solomon's tomb for over 15 years.
我们和你的系主任谈过了
We talked to the dean of your department.
他告诉了我们你的痴迷
He told us about your obsession.
那份痴迷毁掉了你的婚姻  也近乎毁掉了你
How it ruined your marriage and nearly destroyed you.
那不是真的
That is not true.
因为你从未找到那座墓穴
Because you never found that tomb.
你肯定无法忍受
Now, that must have been a bitter pill to swallow,
拉斯用尽你呕心沥血所得的研究成果
knowing that Lars used all of your hard-earned research
找到你未能找到的东西
to find something you never could.
获得你未能获得的
And now he was gonna get all the fame and fortune
名与利
that you never would.
卡塞尔先生  你想象力可真丰富
Mr. Castle, you really do have an overactive imagination.
你没证据证明刚刚编造的故事
You could no more prove that story you just spun
就像你没法向别人证明灯神会从神灯中走出
than you could prove that genies come out of lamps
为你完成三个愿望
and grant three wishes.
其实  我有证据
Actually, that's not true.
警察搜查了你的房子
Uniforms searched your home.
找到了神灯
They found the lamp.
看来你藏宝物的本事
I guess you're as good at hiding treasure
跟你找宝物的本事一样烂
as you are at finding it.
贝克教授  你涉嫌谋杀拉斯·克洛斯和约瑞克·塞曾
Dr. Baker, you're under arrest for the murder of Lars Cross
被拘捕了
and Yuruk Sezen.
你还是小心为好  卡塞尔
You better watch out, Castle.
我可能会偷走你的金发美女哦
I may have to steal your blonde.
我还有两个愿望没有许
I still have two wishes left.
任何摩擦对你来说都没用的
All the rubbing in the world's not gonna do you any good.
我能说"那是她说的"吗
Can I get a "That's what she said"?
那是谁
Oh, who's that?
约旦王室的哈利德·哈西姆王子
Prince Khalid Hasheim of the Jordanian royal family.
他是来保释吉妮维芙的
He's here to bail out Genevieve.
我们似乎找到了神秘的X先生
Methinks we've found our mysterious Mr. X.
哈西姆王子  我是贝克特警监
Prince Hasheim, I'm Captain Beckett.
这位是卡塞尔先生
This is Mr. Castle.
或许我们该叫你X先生
Or perhaps we should call you Mr. X?
X先生是我的雇主
Mr. X is my employer.
他雇佣我保护所罗门墓穴的物品
He paid me to protect the contents of Solomon's Tomb.
没错  虽然我不认识这位先生
Right, well, I don't know this gentleman,
但帮助保护我领土历史的任何人
but anyone who helps protect the history of my region
都值得赞扬
is to be applauded.
当然
Of course.
那些古物和神灯会有什么下场
So, what's gonna happen to the antiquities and the lamp now?
我不是专家
Well, I'm no expert,
但鉴于他们进入这里的方式
but given the way that they entered the country
还和谋杀案有牵扯
and their connection to a murder trial,
他们应该要受到好几年的诉讼保全
they'll be tied up in legal battles for years.
很遗憾听到这样的事
Oh. I'm sorry to hear that.
X先生肯定十分失望吧
I'm sure that Mr. X will be very disappointed
毕竟他如此大费周章地想要获得它们
considering he worked so hard to procure them.
这个我就不得而知了  警监
I don't know about that, Captain.
如果有人希望保护无价的历史
If one wished to keep priceless history safe
不被掠夺和侵犯
from looters and terrorists,
没有什么地方比史密森尼[美国博物馆]地下室
there is no better place for them to wait out the conflict
更安全的了
than in the basement of the Smithsonian.
很高兴认识你们
It was a pleasure meeting you both.
走吧  吉妮
Come along, Genie.
又来了
Here we go again.
她是  那个
That -- She was -- That...
我刚和莱恩通电话了
So, I just got off the phone with Ryan.
珍妮的分娩出了点问题
There's been some complications with Jenny's labor.
本来一切都好好的
Everything was normal, uh...
直到珍妮开始换气过度
until Jenny started hyperventilating.
她现在昏迷了
She lost consciousness.
医生说可能是羊水栓塞
Doctors think it might be a, uh, amniotic fluid embolism.
他们现在在尽力让她稳定
But they're -- they're trying to stabilize her now...
好让孩子生下来
so that, uh... they can deliver the baby.
我们在这儿支持你  需要什么尽管说
We're here, bro, whatever you need.
谢谢
Thanks.
我得进去了
I should get back in there.
我们坐下吧
Let's settle in.
虽然我显然不相信灯神或者许愿
Hey, so, um obviously, I don't believe in genies or wishes,
但假如是真的
but just in case,
你能否用其中一个愿望
I was wondering if you could use one of your wishes
来保佑珍妮和她孩子
for Jenny and the baby.
我已经这么做了
I already did.
两个愿望都用了
Both of them.
好
Okay.
医生稳住了珍妮状况
Uh, doctors -- they stabilized Jenny, and...
她生了个健康的男孩
...she delivered a healthy baby boy.
太好啦
-Yes!
给他起了个什么名字
What's his name?
他的名字是尼古拉斯
Oh. His name is Nicholas...
哈维尔·莱恩
Javier Ryan.
你没在出生证明上拼错名字吧
Tell me you spelled it right on the birth certificate.
我也想要一个
Aww, I want one, too.
如果你再见到那个灯神
So, if you see that, uh, genie again,
能不能告诉她我很感激她
you mind telling her I said thank you?
我已经不相信灯神了
Oh, I think I'm all done with genies.
什么
What?
为什么不相信了
Why the change of heart?
当然是因为你
Well, because of you, of course.
是吗  所以八年了  我的常识终于
Oh, really? So, after eight years, some of my common sense
对你有影响了吗
has finally rubbed off on you?
不是的
No. No, no, no, nothing like that.
我不需要灯神  只是因为
I have no need for genies simply because
我已经拥有了我想要的一切
I already have everything I could ever wish for.
我
I...
对你也是  帅哥
Right back at ya, handsome.
等等  你难道不想要
Oh, wait, um, so, you wouldn't even wish for
有一把光剑吗
a working lightsaber?
不
Nope.
传输机呢  《星际迷航》里的那种
Okay. Transporter, like the ones in "Star Trek"?
有了它你就再也不用坐飞机了
You would never have to fly again.
我喜欢坐飞机
I like flying.
时光机呢
Time machine?
如果是为了回去重新爱上你  那就可以有
Only to go back and fall in love with you all over again.
这个回答很棒
Wow, that was a good answer.
我知道
I know, right?
请让让  爸爸
Make way, Daddy.
珍妮怎么样
How's Jenny?
她累坏了
Oh, she's exhausted.